William J. Huebner Papers VHP2004/9
CCSU Veterans History Project
William J. Huebner Papers
Bulk, 1945-1951
1945, 1950-1951, 1955, 2004
VHP2004/9
CCSU Veterans History Project
17.0 Digital objects
Huebner, William J., 1925 - 2010
Biographical/Historical note
Born in Holyoke, Massachusetts in 1925 William Huebner was drafted into the United States Army in 1943. He served in the South Pacific, New Guinea and the Philippines during World War II. Before his discharge in 1946 William served as Rifleman in the 595th Signal Aircraft Warning Battalion, achieving the rank of Corporal. After World War II he became a Reservist and was once more called to active duty. From 1950 to 1951 William served in the Third Infantry Division in the South Pacific as Staff Sergeant during the Korean War. For his courage and service to the United States military William received the Bronze Star, the Philippine Liberation Medal, the Asiatic Pacific Medal – World War II with one Battle Star, the World War II Victory Medal, the Good Conduct Medal, the United Nations Korean Service Medal, and the Combat Infantry Badge.
Scope and Contents note
This collection details William Huebner’s experiences during his enlistment in World War II and the Korean War. A taped interview was conducted on February 22, 2004 at William’s home by Eileen Hurst. Along with his taped interview the collection contains reproductions of documents and photographs. The materials provide evidence of American troop combat activity, troop deployment, enemy activity and engagement, and U.S. military moral and courage.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Technical metadata of digital objects are extracted and encoded in PREMIS preservation metadata format
Preservation Metadata
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged based on content and material type into 3 series:
Series I, Personal papers
Series II, Military documents
Series III, Multi-media
United States. Army. Signal Aircraft Warning Battalion, 595th .; United States. Army.; Korean War, 1950-1953; War correspondents; World War II - - Personal Narrative, American; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- New Guinea; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Philippines
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1945, 2004
  - Japanese Invasion Money, 1940s; 2004/9.I.1-3; 3.0 Digital objects
  - Interview Synopsis, Feb. 22, 2004; 2004/9.I.4
- Series II: Military Documents, 1943 - 1946
  - "I Cease Resistance" Safe Conduct Passes leaflets written in Japanese, cira 1943 - 1946; 2004/9.II.1; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Propaganda leaflets written in Japanese, cira 1943 - 1946; 2004/9.II.2
- Series III. Multi-Media
  - Subseries A: Still Images, 1950-1951, 1955, 2004
    - Portrait of William J. Huebner in uniform during the Korean War, Dec. 5, 1951; 2004/9.III.1
    - William Huebner wearing cap and sunglasses sitting in a military jeep. He had just been appointed 3rd Infantry Division “correspondent” by General Souel. Korea, 1951 - 1952; 2004/9.III.2
    - Water buffalo pulling a wagon load of supplies. Villagers in background. Korea, 1950 - 1951; 2004/9.III.3
    - Civilians being evacuated from combat zone. Korea, 1950 - 1951; 2004/9.III.4
    - Setting up camp in a cave. Left to right, Dave Brown and Staff Sergeant William Huebner. Korea, 1950 - 1951; 2004/9.III.5
    - Elderly Korean smoking a cigarette. He had been living in a cave for six months. Korea, 1950 - 1951; 2004/9.III.6
    - North Korean infiltrators guarded by armed soldier. The infiltrators were captured while hiding in a rice paddy near Chorwon by U.S. Army 3rd Division. Korea, 1950 - 1952; 2004/9.III.7
    - William Huebner wearing goggles leaning on military jeep. William was a member of the 3rd Infantry Division, Public Relations and G-2 Intelligence Unit. Korea, 1950 - 1951; 2004/9.III.8
    - Flying Boxcar. Lieutenant Colonel Stanley Wojno (right) adjusts William Huebner’s (left) parachute straps prior to take off for Panama. Lt. Col. Wojno was commander of the 337th Troop Carrier Squadron. Bradley Field (Windsor Locks, Conn.)., Dec. 1955; 2004/9.III.9
    - Medals. Photograph of William Huebner’s framed medals and insignia. Avon (Conn.: Town)., Feb. 22, 2004; 2004/9.III.10
  - Subseries B: Moving images, 2004
    - Oral History interview with William J. Huebner, Feb. 22, 2004; 2004/9.IIIb.1 (Disk DVD VHP2004/9, Box VHP Interview 1)
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Interview video also available online.
      Streaming Video